American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIe. 1845-1865 APS.Archives.IIe APS.Archives.IIe
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to R[obert] M. Patterson, June 9, 1846; 8" x 10"; Locke, John, 1792-1856
    Church Landing opposite New Castle, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning magnetic dip in Brandywine hills. See Pro., IV, 268.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, June 9, 1846
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, June 10, 1846; 4 7/8" x 8"; Hays, Isaac, 1796-1879
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests key to cabinet, in order that he may show mastodon bones to Dr. Warren of Boston.
  - Letter to George Ord, June 10, 1846; 5 1/16" x 8 1/16"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning claim of A.P.S. to 131 acre coal field near Shamokin. Suggests an investigation of the claim. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., June 11, 1846; 8" x 10"; M'Ilvaine, Henry
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S Requests return of two Mexican silver drinking cups and cestus, loaned to the A.P.S. by Joseph E. Bloomfield. See Pro., IV, 256.
  - Letter to George Ord, June 11, 1846; 7 7/16" x 9 1/16"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
  - Letter to George Ord, June 20, 1846; 8 1/2" x 11 1/8"; Schmidt, J. W.
    Librarian of the A.P.S., New York, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. The Prussian consul acknowledges receipt of parcel to be sent to the Royal Academy of Sciences at Berlin.
  - Letter to George Ord, June 20, 1846; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Toland, Henry, b. 1785
    Treasurer of A.P.S., New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of package for Bremen, which he will forward by brig Amazon.
  - Letter to George Ord, June 22, 1846; 5" x 7 3/4"; Smith, J. Jay (John Jay), 1798-1881
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Concerning money to be loaned to the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to Isaac Hays, Philadelphia, June 22, 1846; 9x7-1/2; Warren, John Collins, 1778-1856
    Boston, L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Asks permission to make casts of the APS mastodon bones.
  - Letter to [Nathaniel] Chapman, June 24, 1846; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Chauncey, Charles, 1777-1849
    Walnut Street, [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses letter addressed to Mr. Chapman as President of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., June 24, 1846; 9 1/8" x 13 7/8"; Royal Lombardy institute of science
    Letters and Arts to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Milan, 1p. and endorsement. L.S. (In Italian.) Forwards books to, and asks exchange of publications with, the A.P.S. Printed: APS Proceedings, Vol.90,No.5, December, 1946.
  - Letter to George Ord, June 30, 1846; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Dunlap, James D. (James Darwin), 1809-1858
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Erie, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding claim of $65 due to A.P.S. Offers to prosecute the same through his Washington agent, if so desired.
  - Letter to Nathaniel Chapman, June 1846
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, July 6, 1846; 4 1/2" x 7 1/2"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 2 pp. and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of £5. "It is very satisfactory to know that Society has so nearly extricated itself from its difficulties."
  - Settlement with the sheriff on the debt due the estate of Mr. Dunn, July 10, 1846; 6-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p.and end.by George Ord.
  - Letter to George Ord, July 11, 1846; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Dillingham, William H., 1791-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning money to be loaned to the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the Librarian of the A.P.S., July 11, 1846; 4 7/8" x 7 3/4"; Society of Antiquaries of London
    London, 1 p. and endorsement. 3d. per. N. Forwards Archaeologia, XXXI, to the library of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to George Ord, July 13, 1846; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Stoughton, Francisco
    Librarian of A.P.S., Consulate of Spain, New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of parcel for the Royal Academy of History of Madrid.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, July 14, 1846; Abert, John James, 1788-1863
  - Report of committee on paper by Capt. Robert F. Stockton on gunnery, July 17, 1846; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: John F. Frazer and R. M. Patterson. 1p., end. See A.P.S. Proc., IV, 273. Printed: APS Trans., n.s., X, 167-172.
  - Letter to George Ord, July 24, 1846; 7 7/16" x 9 1/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of £5. "We rejoice at the improved state of the affairs of your Society." Settlement of the Oregon question.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., August 1, 1846; 7 3/4" x 12 7/8"; Königlich Preussische Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: J. F. Encke. (In German.) Presents to the A.P.S.: Transactions, 1844; Monthly Reports, July, 1845-June, 1846.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 3, 1846; 10x8; New York Academy of Sciences
    New York, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John H. Redfield. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to [Robley] Dunglison, August 6, 1846; 7 3/4" x 10 1/2"; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Boston, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S.: American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Memoirs, II.
  - Letter to George Ord, August 10, 1846; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Sends designated journals to the A.P.S. by the Philadelphia packet of August 12.
  - Letter to George Ord, August 12, 1846; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Dunlap, James D. (James Darwin), 1809-1858
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Erie, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. With respect to claim of A.P.S. against the government for $65.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., August 12, 1846; 8 1/2" x 11"; Grund, Francis J. (Francis Joseph), 1804-1863
    Consulate of the U. S., Antwerp, 1 p., address and endorsement. L. Forwards package of publications from Academy of Sciences at Brussels.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 14, 1846; 11x8-1/2; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.F.Encke. 1p.,end. In German. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to George Ord, August 18, 1846; 4 7/8" x 7 13/16"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Librarian of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regrets that he failed to see Mr. Ord before leaving for New York.
  - Letter to George Ord, August 18, 1846; 4 1/2" x 7 7/16"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 2 pp. and endorsement. L.S. U. S. tariff on books. "I am very glad to hear that your Society has got through its difficulties.. ."
  - Letter to the Secretary of the [American] Philosophical Society, August 20, 1846; 8 7/8" x 11 7/4"; Brown, John Porter, 1814-1872
    Constantinople, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S.: Grammar of the ottoman Language.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, August 26, 1846; 4 3/8" x 7"; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Secretary of A.P.S., Cambridge, Mass., 2 pp. A.L.S. Concerning volume (from American Academy of Arts and Sciences) lost in mail.
  - Letter to [Robley] Dunglison, September 4, 1846; 8 3/16" x 10 5/8"; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Secretary of A.P.S., Cambridge, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Concerning location of parcels addressed to the Academy [of Natural Sciences] and the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., September 7, 1846; 8 3/8" x 10 5/8"; Whitehead, William A. (William Adee), 1810-1884
    Newark, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S.: a set of the publications of the New Jersey Historical Society.
  - Letter to George Ord, September 10, 1846; 7 3/8" x 9"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.I. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. by the Philadelphia packet September 12.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 22, 1846; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Amsterdam, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.Vrolik. 1p.,end.and add. In French. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, New York, October 1, 1846; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Darby, G. F.
    1 p., address and endorsement. Regarding case to be forwarded to St. Petersburg by the Russian consul. Is glad to hear of Mr. Ord's recovery from sickness.
  - Letter to George Ord, October 2, 1846; 5" x 8 1/8"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has called annual meeting of Wistar party for Saturday evening next.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., October 8, 1846; 4 1/2" x 7 3/8"; Rolandi, Pietro, 1801-1863
    London, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards parcel of books from the Royal Institute of Milan. See Pro., IV, 291.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., October 10, 1846; 8 13/16" x 11 1/8"; Académie royale des sciences de Stockholm
    Stockholm, 1 p. and address. D.S.: C. J. Baikman. (In French.) Presents to the A.P.S.: works listed herein.
  - Letter to the Amer[ican] Philosoph[ical] Society, October 12, 1846; 7 13/16" x 9 7/8"; Nantucket Atheneum
    Nantucket, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S.: W[illia]m Mitchell, President. Requests assistance of A.P.S. in the reestablishment of library destroyed by fire. See Pro., IV, 284.
  - Letter to George Ord, October 12, 1846; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Sends designated journals to the A.P.S. by Philadelphia packet of October 12.
  - Statement of committee on finance regarding payment of debt due to Nathan Dunn, Oct. 16, 1846; 9x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.1p. and end. See APS Proc., IV, 285.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, New York, October 21, 1846; 9" x 11 1/4"; Darby, G. F.
    1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has been unable to locate package about which Mr. Ord inquired in letter of October 13, 1846.
  - Letter to George Ord, October 26, 1846; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Morton, Samuel George, 1799-1851
    Librarian of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Offers books to the A.P.S. in exchange for the skull of a Mexican which he desires to add to his collection. See Pro., IV, 286.
  - Letter to James D. Dunlap, October 27, 1846; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Sherman, Charles E.
    Washington, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding claim of A.P.S. for $65, which dwindled to 65 cents. Enclosed in Dunlap to Ord, October 28, 1847.
  - Statement to [Petty] Vaughan of publications sent to the American philosophical society, Oct. 31, 1846; 5x8; Taylor, Richard & John, printers
    D. 1p.,end.and end. Was not paid since Sir William Jardine accepted APS Transactions in return.
  - Letter to George Ord, November 3, 1846; 7 3/8" x 9"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 2 pp., address and endorsement. Regarding designated journals, forwarded to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the [American] Philosophical Society, November 10, 1846; 7 3/4" x 10"; Nürnberger, Joseph Emil, 1779-1848
    Landsberg, Germany, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. (In German.) ---1 p. English translation. Sends to the A.P.S.: a copy of his Astonomical Dictionary.
  - Letter to R[obley] Dunglison, Nov. 11, 1846; 10x8; New York State Library
    Printed L.filled in in ms. S.: T.Romeyn Beck. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Isaac Lea, November 12, 1846; 8 1/8" x 12 1/4"; Haldeman, Samuel Steman, 1812-1880
    Philadelphia, 1p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Corrections for his paper on Longicornia, See Pro., IV, 298.
  - Letter to George Ord, November 18, 1846; 4 1/2" x 7 1/2"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p. L.S. Concerning parcel sent to A.P.S. by the T. P. Cope but not received.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, Philadelphia, Nov. 19, 1846; 10-1/4x8; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Flourens. 2p.,end. In French. Thanks for publications.
  - Report of committee of board of officers on 'Treatise on the parallactic eyepiece" offered for Magellanic premium, Nov. 20, 1846; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: R.M. Patterson and Joseph Henry. 1p. and end. See APS Proc., IV, 294.
  - Letterto Geo[rge] Ord, November 30, 1846; 7 1/2" x 9 5/8"; Watson, John F. (John Fanning), 1779-1860
    Germantown, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests permission to copy "autograph papers of the olden time" of sufficient interest for publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 1, 1846; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S: Edward Everett, Pres.and Thaddeus William Harris, Librarian. 1p.,end.and add.: Care of Dr. A. L. Elwyn. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - A new theory of imponderables., December 4, 1846; 8" x 10"; Norton, William A. (William Augustus), 1810-1883
    35 pp. and endorsement. Com. See Pro., IV, 296, 332.
  - Letter to the President of the APS, Philadelphia, Dec. 4, 1846; 10x7-1/2; Plumbe, John, 1809-1857
    A.L.S. 1p.,end.and add. Wishes to copy the Jefferson portrait. Film 199 Frame 216
  - Letter to Rob[er]t [M.] Patterson, December 9, 1846; 7 7/8" x 10"; Norton, William A. (William Augustus), 1810-1883
    Newark, Del., 1 p. A.L.S. Explanation of isothermal or isogeothermal lines used in his paper.
  - Letter to George Ord, December 9, 1846; 7 3/8" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. by the Saranak.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, December 9, 1846; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Western University of Pennsylvania
    [Pittsburgh], 2 pp., address and endorsement. Requesting aid from the A.P.S. to restore their library, destroyed by fire. See Pro. IV, 300.
  - Receipt to the American Philosophical society for payment to Alderman Smith for proceedings against Charles Naylor, Dec. 14, 1846; 4x8; Ord, George, 1781-1866
  - Receipt to the American philosophical society for proceedings against Charles Naylor, Dec. 14, 1846; 5x8; Smith, Thomas D.
    D.S. 1p.and end. by George Ord.
  - Letter to [the American Philosophical Society], December 14, 1846; 7 1/2" x 10 1/8"; Watson, John F. (John Fanning), 1779-1860
    Germantown, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Asks permission to use manuscripts in possession of the A.P.S. in furtherance of historical researches undertaken by himself and John Jay Smith. See Pro., IV, 296.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., December 16, 1846; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Blickensderfer, Jacob, 1816-1899
    Columbus, O[hio], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires as to availability and price of back issues of A.P.S. Proceedings and Transactions.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, December 18, 1846; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Baena, Antonio, 1782-1850
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Para, 1p. and endorsement. A.L.S. (In Protuguese.)
  - Report of committee on W[illia]m McIlvaine's supplement to his "Perpetual calendar", Dec. 19, 1846; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: R.M. Patterson and John F. Frazer. 1p. and end. See Proc., IV, 297-296.
  - Letter to George Ord, December 23, 1846; 8 1/4" x 10 5/8"; Wiley & Putnam
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. "We are not aware that Mr. Rolandi has given any instructions relative to packages for the Milan Institute, but we can...forward any package to Mr. Rolandi..."
  - Ricerche fisico-chimico-fisiologiche sulla luce..., 1846; Zantedeschi, Francesco, 1797-1873
    Venezia, Antonelli, The APS does not possess this publication, but Zantedeschi sent a manuscript copy of the third chapter to the society and it may be found under: Zantedeschi,F. Dei risultamenti attenuati da una nuova analisi...; [Feb.1864]. APS Archives. Not found May 2011.
  - Letter to George Ord, January 2, 1847; 3 7/8" x 5 1/2"; Morton, Samuel George, 1799-1851
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Wishes to borrow the Transactions of the Berlin Academy for 1827, in order that Mr. [Victor G.] Audubon may translate an article contained therein.
  - Letter to George Ord, January 6, 1847; 6 3/16" x 7 1/2"; Watson, John F. (John Fanning), 1779-1860
    Germantown, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. "I hear, with pleasure, that I am to be indulged in the examination of the Franklin papers. ..." FILM54-61 FRAME143.
  - Letter to George Ord, January 8, 1847; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Holbrook, John Edwards, 1794-1871
    Charleston, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Requests Mr. Ord to obtain certain data for him from [carolus] Linnaeus, Systemanaturae.
  - Letter to George Ord, January 9, 1847; 7 1/2" x 12 3/8"; Watson, John F. (John Fanning), 1779-1860
    Germantown, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Method of studying historical source material. Cooperation with [American Philosophical] Society.
  - Report of librarian against donating books to Western University of Pennsylvania at Pittsburgh, Jan. 11, 1847; 12x8; American Philosophical Society. Library
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: G. Ord. 1p. See APS Proc., IV, 302.
  - Letter to George Ord, January 11, 1847; 7 3/8" x 9 3/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is forwarding designated journals to the A.P.S. by the Philadelphia packet of January 12.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, January 14, 1847; 8 1/4" x 10 5/8"; Angelis, Pedro de, 1784-1859
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Buenos Ayres, 2 pp. A.L.S. (In French.) Forwards collection of documents relating to the intervention of England and France in the Rio de la Plata.
  - Letter to George Ord, January 20, 1847; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Rolandi, Pietro, 1801-1863
    London, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges letter of [December] 29, [1846], "and am glad to hear that the books sent by the Royal Institute of Milan have arrived safe."
  - Letter to [the American Philosophical Society], January 26, 1847; 7 7/8" x 9"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. Pr.D. Sends to the A.P.S.: maps of New Haven and Little Egg Harbor.
  - Letter to [George] Ord, Librarian of A.P.S., January 29, 1847; 5" x 8"; Palmer, W. R. (William R.), d. 1862
    Philadelphia, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests that the distribution of Major J.D. Graham's paper on the magnetic dip be delayed until publication of list of errata.
  - Letter to George Ord, February 4, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Librarian of A.P.S., Washington, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. With regard to the printing of a list of errata for his article on the magnetic dip. See W. R. Palmer to [George] Ord, January 29, 1847.
  - Report of committee on paper by [Charles D.] Meigs "On the corpus luteum", Feb. 5, 1847; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: W. E. Horner, Paul B. Goddard, and Robley Dunglison. 1p. and end. See APS Proc., IV, 305-307. Printed: APS Trans., n.s., X, 131-139.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, February 6, 1847; 4 1/2" x 7 1/2"; Morton, Samuel George, 1799-1851
    [Philadelphia]. 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Returns Transactions of Berlin Academy, from which Mr. [Victor G.] Audubon translated an article.
  - Letter to Secretary of the A.P.S., February 9, 1847; 8" x 9 3/4"; Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester
    [Manchester], 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S.: Memoirs, VII, pt. 2.
  - Letter to George Ord, February 10, 1847; 7 3/8" x 9 3/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of books for Sir William Jardine. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to [George] Ord, February 19, 1847; 4 3/4" x 7 9/16"; Downes, John
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Wishes to renew the loan of specified astronomical books borrowed from A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, Philadelphia, Feb. 22, 1847; 10-3/4x8-1/2; New Jersey Historical Society
    Newark, A.L.S.: W.A.Whitehead. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 28, 1847; 9-3/4x8; Bowditch Library
    A.L.S.: H.I.Bowditch. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to George Ord, Librarian of A.P.S., February 28, 1847; 8 3/8" x 11 3/4"; Bonaparte, Charles Lucian, 1803-1857
    Rome, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Returns thanks for election of Joseph Ceva Grimaldi, Marquis of Pietracatella, to membership in the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., February, 1847; 7 1/4" x 9 1/8"; Haidinger, Wilhelm, 1795-1871
    Vienna, --, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S. Prince Metternich presents to the A.P.S. a recently published volume on palaeontology.
  - Letter to George Ord, March 9, 1847; 7 7/16" x 9 3/16"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. library by the Wyoming.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Campbell, March 10, 1847; 7 15/16" x 10"; Roberts, Solomon W. (Solomon White), 1811-1882
    Harrisburg, 2pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Mr. Trego has attached memorial of A.P.S. to bill in the House "and in that way our supplement has passed the House without objection."
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Campbell, March 12, 1847; 7 15/16" x 10"; Roberts, Solomon W. (Solomon White), 1811-1882
    Harrisburg, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Bill of the American Philosophical Society, having passed the House, will be attended to by Mr. Crabb in the Senate.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Campbell, March 13, 1847; 7 15/16" x 10"; Roberts, Solomon W. (Solomon White), 1811-1882
    Harrisburg, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. American Philosophical Society bill passed Senate and "is now in the hands of the Governor for his signature."
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Campbell, March 17, 1847; 7 15/16" x 10"; Roberts, Solomon W. (Solomon White), 1811-1882
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends certified copy of "An Act relative to the American Philosophical Society."
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], March 19, 1847; 11x8-1/2; Hammer-Purgstall, Joseph, Frieherr von, 1774-1856
    Vienna, A.L.S. 1p.,end.by G.Ord. His copies of Proceedings stopped in 1844 and wishes them brought to date.
  - Payment of one-fourth of back interest in coal script to the American philosophical society, April 1, 1847; 7x8; Lehigh Coal & Navigation Company
    D.in hand of George Ord. 1p.and end.
  - Report of committee on paper by Sears C. Walker on the planet Neptune, April 2, 1847; 8x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: R. M. Patterson and John Downes. 1p. See APS Proc., IV,, 324. Printed: Trans., n.s., X, 141-153.
  - Report of committee on election laws, April 2, 1847; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: J. K. Kane, Geo. W. Bethune and John Ludlow. 1p. and end. See APS Proc., IV, 324.
  - Letter to George Ord, April 10, 1847; 7 3/8" x 9 1/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. by the Saranac.
  - Report of committee on paper by Prof. Tucker on "Cause and effect;", April 15, 1847; 9x7; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Alonzo Potter, Ch[arle]s R. Demme, and Geo. W. Bethune. 3p. and end.
  - Report of committee on paper by Ch[arles] D. Meigs on the "Reproduction of the opossum", April 15, 1847; 9x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: Isaac Hays and Franklin Bache. 1p. and end. See APS Proc., IV, 327-330. Printed: APS Trans., n.s., X, 155-166.
  - Letter to George Ord, April 15, 1847; 7 3/8" x 9 1/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850